A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Controller FA215
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Controller
1902-1971
Rockefeller Archive Center
Lyons, David J.
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA215
1.31 Cubic Feet 1 box.
Biographical/Historical note
In 1970/1971 David J. Lyons came to the University as Director of Economic Planning. In 1971/1972 he was named Controller, an executive officer which he remained until the fall of 1978.
In 1978 with Dr. Joshua Lederberg, the new president of the University, Mr. Lyons was elected a Vice President of the University to continue as Controller but with new managerial responsibilities.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 240
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: photographs, ledgers, and account books.
- Photographs (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Ledgers and Account Books, 1906-1971; microforms.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Individual microforms may be restricted from scholarly access due to preservation concerns.
  - Cash Disbursements, 1956 November-1957 June (Box 1, Roll 1)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1957 July-1958 May (Box 1, Roll 2)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1958 June-1959 March (Box 1, Roll 3)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1959 April-1960 January (Box 1, Roll 4)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1960 February-November (Box 1, Roll 5)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1960 December-1961 September (Box 1, Roll 6)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1961 October-1962 June (Box 1, Roll 7)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1962 July-1963 April (Box 1, Roll 8)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1963 May-December (Box 1, Roll 9)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1964 January-September (Box 1, Roll 10)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1964 October-1965 May (Box 1, Roll 11)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1965 June-1966 February (Box 1, Roll 12)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1966 March-October (Box 1, Roll 13)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1966 November-1967 May (Box 1, Roll 14)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1967 June-November (Box 1, Roll 15)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1967 December-1968 May (Box 1, Roll 16)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1968 June-November (Box 1, Roll 17)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1968 December-1969 May (Box 1, Roll 18)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1969 June-November (Box 1, Roll 19)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1969 December-1970 May (Box 1, Roll 20)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1970 June-November (Box 1, Roll 21)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1970 December-1971 May (Box 1, Roll 22)
  - Cash Disbursements, 1971 June-October (Box 1, Roll 23)
  - Cash Receipts, 1956 November-1960 June (Box 1, Roll 24)
  - Cash Receipts, 1960 July-1962 December (Box 1, Roll 25)
  - Cash Receipts, 1963 January-1965 May (Box 1, Roll 26)
  - Cash Receipts, 1965 June-1967 June (Box 1, Roll 27)
  - Cash Receipts, 1967 July-1969 June (Box 1, Roll 28)
  - Cash Receipts July 1969 - Sundry Persons Ledger June 1959, 1959-1969 (Box 1, Roll 29)
  - Sundry Persons Ledger, 1959 July-1962 June (Box 1, Roll 30)
  - Sundry Persons Ledger July, 1962-1965 June (Box 1, Roll 31)
  - Sundry Persons Ledger July 1965 - Distribution Book June 1914 (Box 1, Roll 32)
  - Distribution Book July 1914 - General Ledger June 1919 (Box 1, Roll 33)
  - General Ledger July 1919 - Laboratory and Hospital Ledger December 1929 (Box 1, Roll 34)
  - Account Book 1913 - Laboratory and Hospital Ledger 1951 (Box 1, Roll 35)
  - Comparative Record 1940-1945 - Cash Book Pages - December 31, 1958 (Box 1, Roll 36)
  - General Ledger Rockefeller, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Roll 36A)
  - Faculty/Student Club Journal 1959 - Account Book Depts. 20, 60, and H70 1933 (Box 1, Roll 37)
  - Payroll Deduction Register, 1967 January-1967 February 15 (Box 1, Roll 38)
  - Payroll Deduction Register, 1967 February 15-1967 March (Box 1, Roll 39)
  - Payroll Deduction Register, 1967 April-1967 May 17 (Box 1, Roll 40)
  - Payroll Deduction Register, 1967 May-June (Box 1, Roll 41)
  - Payroll Deduction Register, 1967 July-1967 August 16 (Box 1, Roll 42)
  - Payroll Deduction Register, 1967 August 15-1967 September 15 (Box 1, Roll 43)
  - Payroll Deduction Register, 1967 September 6-1967 October (Box 1, Roll 44)
  - Payroll Deduction Register, 1967 November-December (Box 1, Roll 45)
  - Payroll Deduction Register, 1967 December-1968 February (Box 1, Roll 46)
  - Payroll Deduction Register, 1968 March-April (Box 1, Roll 47)
  - Payroll Deduction Register, 1968 April-June (Box 1, Roll 48)
  - Chemical Bank 1960, vol. 117 - 1965, vol. 144, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Roll 49)
  - Chemical Bank 1965, vol. 145 - Corn Exchange Bank 1965, vol. 183 (Box 1, Roll 50)
  - Corn Exchange Bank March 1959/May 1963, vol. 184 - Farm Account Journal 1912, vol. 202, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Roll 51)
  - Trial Balance 1917/1921, vol. 203 - Trail Balance (Maintenance) December 1925/February 1927, vol. 216, 1917-1927 (Box 1, Roll 52)
  - Trial Balance 1937/1939 - Laboratory Ledger 10/33-11/34, vol. 230 (Box 1, Roll 53)
  - RIMR Petty Cash 1923/1924, vol. 231 - Journal Vouchers 1919, vol. 239 (Box 1, Roll 54)
  - RIMR at NY Physical Plant Charges 1914/1921, vol. 240 - Distribution 1910/1913, vol. 248 (Box 1, Roll 55)
  - Special Ledger 1906/1911, vol. 249 - Rockefeller Institute Contingent Fund 1917/1955, vol. 257 (Box 1, Roll 56)
  - Animal Book 1918/1926, vol. 258 - Student and Faculty Club Check Stubs 1963/1965, vol. 261 (Box 1, Roll 57)
  - Cash Book Folios vol. 262 - Cash Book, RIMR vol. 264 (Box 1, Roll 58)
    Scope and Contents
    Start: Cash Book Folios July 1, 1948.
    End: Cash Book, RIMR July 1917-February 1918.
  - Cash Book, RIMR vol. 265 - vol. 268, p. 109 (Box 1, Roll 59)
    Start: Cash Book, RIMR No. 1 March 1918-June 1920 1/ Vol. 265
    End: Cash Book, RIMR No. 4 Sept. 1926 Pq. 109 2/Vol. 268
  - Cash Book, RIMR vol. 268, p. 110 - vol. 271, p. 133 (Box 1, Roll 60)
    Start: Cash Book, RIMR No. 4 October 1926 Pq. 110 2/Vol. 268
    End: Cash Book, RIMR No. 7, General Acct December 1932 Pq. 133 2/Vol. 271
  - Cash Book, RIMR vol. 271, p. 134 - vol. 273 (Box 1, Roll 61)
    Start: Cash Book, RIMR No. 7 General Acct, January 1933, Pq. 134 2/Vol. 271
    End: Cash Book, RIMR No. 9 July, 1935-June, 1937 3/Vol. 273
  - Cash Book, RIMR vol. 274 - vol. 276, p. 163 (Box 1, Roll 62)
    Start: Cash Book, RIMR No. 10 July 1937-June, 1939 3/Vol. 274
    End: Cash Book, RIMR No. 12, General Acct, December 1942 Pq. 163 3/Vol. 276
  - Cash Book, RIMR vol. 276, p. 164 - vol. 278, p. 306 (Box 1, Roll 63)
    Start: Cash Book, RIMR No. 12 General Acct, January 1943 Pq. 164 3/Vol. 276
    End: Cash RIMR No. 14 Payroll June 1946 Pq. 306 4/Vol. 278
  - Cash Book, RIMR vol. 278, p. 307 - vol. 280 (Box 1, Roll 64)
    Start: Cash Book, RIMR No. 14 Payroll July 1947 Pq. 307 4/Vol. 278
    End: Cash Book, RIMR No. 16 July 1949-June 1951 4/Vol. 280
  - Cash Book, RIMR vol. 281 - vol. 283, p. 157 (Box 1, Roll 65)
    Start: Cash Book, RIMR No: 17 July 1951-June 1953 Vol. 281
    End: Cash Book, RIMR No. 19 - General Acct, July 1956, Page 157 5/Vol. 283
  - Cash Book, RIMR vol. 283, p. 158 - General Ledger Transfer vol. 286 (Box 1, Roll 66)
    Start: Cash Book, RIMR No. 19 - General Acct, July 1956, Page 158 5/Vol. 283 [UNREADABLE]
    End: General Ledger Transfer 1923-1924 6/Vol. 286
  - General Ledger Transfer vol. 287 - vol. 290 (Box 1, Roll 67)
    Start: RIMR General Ledger Transfer 1924-1925 6/Vol. 287
    End: RIMR General Ledger Transfer 1927-1928 6/Vol. 290
  - General Ledger Transfer vol. 291 - vol. 294 (Box 1, Roll 68)
    Start: RIMR General Ledger Transfer 1928-1929 6/Vol. 291
    End: RIMR General Ledger Transfer 1931-1932 7/Vol. 294
  - General Ledger Transfer vol. 295 - vol. 298 (Box 1, Roll 69)
    Start: RIMR General Ledger Transfer 1932-1933 7/Vol. 295
    End: RIMR General Ledger Transfer 1935-1936 7/Vol. 298
  - General Ledger Transfer vol. 299 - vol. 302 (Box 1, Roll 70)
    Start: General Ledger Transfer 1936-1937 8/Vol. 299
    End: General Ledger Transfer 1939-1940 8/Vol. 302
  - General Ledger Transfer vol. 303 - vol. 305 (Box 1, Roll 71)
    Start: General Ledger Transfer 1940-1941 8/Vol. 303
    End: General Ledger Transfer 1942-1943 9/Vol. 305
  - General Ledger Transfer vol. 306 - vol. 308 (Box 1, Roll 72)
    Start: General Ledger Transfer 1943-1944 9/Vol. 306
    End: General Ledger Transfer 1945-1946 9/Vol. 308
  - General Ledger Transfer vol. 309 - vol. 311 (Box 1, Roll 73)
    Start: General Ledger Transfer 1946-1947 10/Vol. 309
    End: General Ledger Transfer 1948-1949 10/Vol. 311
  - General Ledger Transfer vol. 312 - vol. 314 (Box 1, Roll 74)
    Start: General Ledger Transfer 1949-1950 10/Vol. 312
    End: General Ledger Transfer 1951-1952 11/Vol. 314
  - General Ledger Transfer vol. 315 - vol. 317 (Box 1, Roll 75)
    Start: General Ledger Transfer 1952-1953 11/Vol. 315
    End: General Ledger Transfer 1954-1955 11/Vol. 317
  - General Ledger Transfer vol. 318 - War Demonstration Hospital vol. 319 (Box 1, Roll 76)
    Start: General Ledger Transfer 1955-1956 [unreadable]
    End: War Demonstration Hospital 1917-1920 [unreadable]
  - Princeton Voucher Register no. 1, 1917-1918, vol. 320 - no. 6, 1928-1930, vol. 325, 1917-1930 (Box 1, Roll 77)
  - Princeton Voucher Register no. 7, 1930-1933, vol. 326 - no. 9, 1933-1936, vol. 328, 1930-1936 (Box 1, Roll 78)
  - Princeton Voucher Register no. 10, 1939-1942, vol. 329 - no. 12, 1946-1951, vol. 331, 1939-1951 (Box 1, Roll 79)
  - Hospital Voucher Register no. 1, 1910-1913, vol. 332 - no. 2, 1921-1923, vol. 337, 1910-1923 (Box 1, Roll 80)
  - Hospital Voucher Register no. 3, 1923-1925, vol. 338 - no. 7, 1932-1936, vol. 342, 1923-1936 (Box 1, Roll 81)
  - Hospital Voucher Register no. 8, 1936-1941, vol. 343 - no. 10, 1946-1952, vol. 345, 1936-1952 (Box 1, Roll 82)
  - Hospital Voucher Register no. 11, 1952-1956, vol. 346 - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 4, June 1915, vol. 350 (Box 1, Roll 83)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 5, July 1915 - June 1916, vol. 351 - no. 9, July 1919 - June 1920, vol. 355, 1915-1920 (Box 1, Roll 84)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 10, July 1920 - June 1921, vol. 356 - no. 13, July 1923 - June 1924, vol. 359, 1920-1924 (Box 1, Roll 85)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 14, July 1924 - June 1925, vol. 360 - no. 16, June 1926 - June 1927, vol. 362, 1924-1927 (Box 1, Roll 86)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 17, July 1927 - June 1928, vol. 363 - no. 19, July 1929 - June 1930, vol. 365, 1927-1930 (Box 1, Roll 87)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 20, July 1930 - June 1931, vol. 366 - no. 22, July 1932 - June 1933, vol. 368, 1930-1933 (Box 1, Roll 88)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 23, July 1933 - June 1934, vol. 369 - no. 25, July 1935 - June 1936, vol. 371, 1933-1936 (Box 1, Roll 89)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 26, July 1936 - June 1937, vol. 372 - no. 28, July 1938 - June 1939, vol. 374, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Roll 90)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 29, July 1939 - June 1940, vol. 375 - no. 31, July 1941 - June 1942, vol. 377, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Roll 91)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 32, July 1942 - June 1943, vol. 378 - no. 34, July 1944 - June 1945, vol. 380, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Roll 92)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 35, July 1945 - June 1946, vol. 381 - no. 37, July 1947 - June 1948, vol. 383, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Roll 93)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 38, July 1948 - June 1949, vol. 384 - no. 40, July 1950 - June 1951, vol. 386, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Roll 94)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register no. 41, July 1951 - June 1954 - no. 42, July 1954 - June 1958, 1951-1958 (Box 1, Roll 95)
  - Laboratory Voucher Register July 1954 - June 1955, vol 391 - July 1956 - October 1956, vol. 396, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Roll 96)
  - Journal Vouchers July 1917-1919, vol. 397 (Box 1, Roll 97)
  - Journal Vouchers 1919-1920, vol. 398 - 1921-1922, vol. 400, 1919-1922 (Box 1, Roll 98)
  - Journal Vouchers 1922-1923, vol. 401 - Journal Vouchers, 1924-1925, vol. 403, 1922-1925 (Box 1, Roll 99)
  - Journal Vouchers 1925-1926, vol. 404 - 1927-1928, vol. 406, 1925-1928 (Box 1, Roll 100)
  - Journal Vouchers 1928-1929, vol. 407 - 1930-1931, vol. 409, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Roll 101)
  - Journal Vouchers 1931-1932, vol. 410 - 1933-1934, vol. 412, 1931-1934 (Box 1, Roll 102)
  - Journal Vouchers 1934-1935, vol. 413 - 1936-1937, vol. 415, 1934-1937 (Box 1, Roll 103)
  - Journal Vouchers 1937-1938, vol. 416 - 1938-1939, vol. 417, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Roll 104)
  - Journal Vouchers 1939-1940, vol. 418 - 1940-1941, vol. 419, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Roll 105)
  - Journal Vouchers 1941-1942, vol. 420 - 1942-1943, vol. 421, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Roll 106)
  - Journal Vouchers 1943-1944, vol. 422 - 1944-1945, vol. 423, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Roll 107)
  - Journal Vouchers 1945-1946, vol. 424 - 1946-1947, vol. 425, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Roll 108)
  - Journal Vouchers 1947-1948, vol. 426 - 1948-1949, vol. 427, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Roll 109)
  - Journal Vouchers 1949-1950, vol. 428 - 1951-1952, vol. 430, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Roll 110)
  - Journal Vouchers 1952-1953, vol. 431 - 1955-1956, vol. 434, 1952-1956 (Box 1, Roll 111)
  - Petty Cash July 1956 - June 1957, vol. 435 - Petty Cash Payroll 1961-1962, vol. 440, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Roll 112)
  - Petty Cash Payroll 1962-1963, vol. 441 - Monthly Salary Account 1957-1958, vol. 447, 1957-1963 (Box 1, Roll 113)
  - Monthly Payroll 1958-1959, vol. 448 - Monthly Payroll 1962-1963, vol. 452, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Roll 114)
  - Monthly Payroll 1963-1964, vol. 453 - Monthly Payroll 1966-1967, vol. 456, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Roll 115)
  - Semi-monthly Payroll 1956-1957, vol. 457 - 1957-1958, vol. 458, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Roll 116)
  - Semi-monthly Payroll 1958-1959, vol. 459 - 1959-1960, vol. 460, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Roll 117)
  - Semi-monthly Payroll 1960-1961, vol. 461 (Box 1, Roll 118)
  - Semi-monthly Payroll 1961-1962, vol. 462 (Box 1, Roll 119)
  - Semi-monthly Payroll 1962-1963, vol. 463 (Box 1, Roll 120)
  - Semi-monthly Payroll 1963-1964, vol. 464 (Box 1, Roll 121)
  - Semi-monthly Payroll 1964-1965, vol. 465 (Box 1, Roll 122)
  - Semi-monthly Payroll 1965-1966, vol. 466 (Box 1, Roll 123)
  - Semi-monthly Payroll 1966, vol. 467 (Box 1, Roll 124)